Guide to the Frank Sullivan collection, 1910-1972.
Sullivan, Frank collection, 1910-1972.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frank Sullivan collection, 1910-1972.
4618
Frank Sullivan, 1892-1976.
4 linear ft.
Correspondence, newspapers, programs, and essays.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and other papers of Frank Sullivan, an American journalist, humorist and author who was long associated with the New Yorker magazine.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
American journalist, humorist and author, long associated with the New Yorker magazine, whose Christmas poem he composed each year for 50 years. Also a member of the Algonquin Round Table literary gathering in the 1920's.
Cornell University Class of 1914.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Consists mainly of correspondence, including letters by Sullivan (chiefly from 1925-1945), mostly personal, but some concerning publication of his books and articles for the New York World, the New Yorker, and the Saturday Evening Post. Includes correspondence with J.M. Dent & Sons about Sullivan's book Sullivan at Bay (London, 1939); with George Oppenheimer at Viking Press about Frank Sullivan Through the Looking-Glass, which Oppenheimer edited; and with other journalists and editors, especially New Yorker staff. Also included are issues of the Cornell Daily Sun and program for Cornell events from 1910-1914; programs for plays performed at the Lyceum Theater, Ithaca, N.Y., from 1912-1913; and essays Sullivan wrote for an English course at Cornell in 1912, with his professor's comments.
Correspondents include William Jacob Cuppy, Margaret Feldman, Corey Ford, Ann Honeycutt, J.M. Dent & Sons, Kenneth Kirkpatrick, Adele Lovett, George Oppenheimer, Harold Ross, Alison Smith, E.B. White, Katharine Sergeant White, Alexander Woollcott; Little, Brown & Co., Gus Lobrano, James Thurber, and P.G. Wodehouse. Also included are 3 letters to Sullivan from James Cagney and 2 letters to him from Eleanor Roosevelt.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sullivan, Frank, 1892-1976.; Cagney, James, 1899-1986.; Cuppy, Will, 1884-1949.; Feldman, Margaret.; Ford, Corey, 1902-1969.; Honeycutt, Ann.; Kirkpatrick, Kenneth.; Lobrano, Gustav Stubbs.; Lovett, Adele.; Oppenheimer, George.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Ross, Harold Wallace, 1892-1951.; Smith, Alison.; Sullivan, Frank, 1892-1976.; White, E. B. (Elwyn Brooks), 1899-; White, Katharine Sergeant Angell.; Wodehouse, P. G. (Pelham Grenville), 1881-1975.; Woollcott, Alexander, 1887-1943.; Cornell University--History.; Cornell University--Students.; J.M. Dent and Sons.; Little, Brown and Company.; Lyceum Theater (Ithaca, N.Y.); Viking Press.
Titles:
New Yorker (New York, N.Y.: 1925); Cornell Daily Sun.
Subjects:
American periodicals.; American literature--20th century.; American wit and humor.; Theater--United States--History--20th century.; Theater--New York (State)--Ithaca.; English literature--Study and teaching.; Authors, American.; Journalists; Humorists, American.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--History.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related collections of the papers of New Yorker staff are held in the repository, including papers of A.J. Liebling, E.B. White, and James Thurber.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Letters to Sullivan arranged alphabetically by correspondent; letters by Sullivan in chronological order.
CONTAINER LIST
- Manuscripts and documents (Box 1)
- Outgoing correspondence
  - Undated (Box 2)
  - 1913-1932 (Box 3)
  - 1933-1938 (Box 4)
  - 1938-1947 (Box 5)
  - 1948-1965 (Box 6)
  - 1965- (Box 7)
- Incoming correspondence
  - A-I (Box 8)
  - J-Ln (Box 9)
  - Lo-Rose (Box 10)
  - Ross-St (Box 11)
  - Su-Z (Box 12)
- Clippings and Sullivaniana (Box 13)